S. Naresh

Deputy General Manager

Aarvee Associates Architects. Pvt Ltd.



+91 9437069364



sadineni.naresh@gmail.com



Chinnapavani Post, Prakasam District, Andhra Pradesh -523115

Deputy General Manager with **19+ years of experience** in ensuring that all projects are delivered on time, within the scope, and within budget; assisting in the definition of project scope and objectives. Now seeking an opportunity to utilize my extensive experience with construction procedures and leadership and make a significant contribution to the company's success, thus driving the organization to the next level of excellence.

TOTAL EXPERIENCE – 19+ YEARS

- > 7 years' experience in Industrial and Internal Road works
- 5 years' experience in Irrigation work
- > 7+ years' experience in Railway works (WDFCC & Metro)

SKILLS

- Project Management.
- Construction Management.
- Vendor Management.
- Strategic Planning.
- Cost Estimation.
- Project planning & coordination.

FIELD EXPOSURE

- Irrigation
- Industrial work
- Railway and Road embankments and structures.
- Canal Lining Works

EDUCATION

B. Tech - Civil

PMP certification from PMI COMPUTER SKILLS

strong working knowledge of Microsoft Office and AUTO CAD

EXECUTIVE SYNOPSYS

- Extensive experience in Project Management of Govt. Funded projects such as Roadways, Irrigation, WFDCC and Metro development works, whose valuations are more than ₹1000 Cr.
- Adept at leading cross-functional teams and managing the end-to-end process right from evaluating BOQs, Manpower allocations, execution of projects, matching the deadlines, generating the running bill, invoicing, dispute management, quality assurance to hand-over of projects.
- Comprehensive technical expertise in all construction methodologies and procedures to be carried out before, during, and postconstruction.
- Specialized in onsite technical administration of construction, supervision, team allocations, and coordinating with the project team, consultants, architects, etc. for quality assurance.
- Capable of identifying risks, and dependencies, and managing them.
 Has hands-on experience in creating workflow graphs sheets using appropriate
- Result-oriented team player with excellent leadership abilities and time management skills, effective communicator & relationship manager, prioritizing and multi-tasking skills, and ability to turn around projects under strict deadlines and budgetary constraints.
- Proactive achievement-driven professional with a strong work ethic, integrity, and excellent communicating, coordinating, problemsolving, decision-making, planning, and executing skills.
- Knows the ropes of construction of industrial drainage systems, irrigation work, WDFCC and Canal work, etc., with tremendous work pressure and strict rules. Has a sound knowledge implementation of safety norms and regulations

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Aarvee Associates Architects Engineers & Consultants PVT.LTD

2023 – Till.

Deputy General Manager Pkg-C1 (RE Metro) Metro Rail U girder, I Girder casting and erection and construction of Metro stations and construction of Extra Dose Bridges etc. at **Ahmedabad Metro rail Phase 2.**

L&T Construction TIIC.

2019-2023

As Sr. Construction Manager Pkg-C (package Head formation & Structures) Railway structures and formation works. (Structures Concrete works 80,000 Cum MJB, MIB, RUB, ROB, TRC & ERS Etc. and Earth Formation works 70 lacs cum we have completed in WDFC project.)

•	M/S Gayatri projects Ltd As Project Manager at Tata steel Railway & Structures, RM 4,5,7&8 Buildings and SWD system, RMHS works Coal Yard Works and DMRC Metro works. (Likely 1,68,000 cum concrete works We have completed in TATA steel and 70 lacs cum Formation Works completed in WDFC project.)	2011 – 2019
•	M/S Rohini Construction	2009 – 2011
•	As Manager we have done Madduvalasa 5000 Acr water supply work with main canal Lining and structures works done under Srikakulam Division Andhra Pradesh. M/S Ratna Infrastructures Pvt Ltd As Senior Engineer Canal lining and Structures works done under Dabara Division CG & BSP Steel plant works.	2007 – 2009
•	M/s. A P R & Co Junior Engineer main canal Lining and structures under Rani Avanti bhai projects	2005 – 2007

JOB RESPONSIBILITIES

Division Bhelkedi division MP.

- Operates as a critical member of the corporate team in the Construction Division's strategic planning initiatives. Attend client meetings, before the commencement of projects to get familiar with them.
- Evaluate, and study various drawings and documents to know the project with teams to understand the scope of work and schedule out the activities, find any loopholes in design, and provide engineering/ design ideas solutions to management for achieving and maintaining the quality of work.
- Regulate the Timelines and Milestones for the execution of project, and assign tasks to teams to carry out the preparation of cost estimates, cost analysis, and budgets for a project with projected forecasts. Evaluate the estimates minutely and rectify budget optimizations.
- Update, review and monitor the detailed planning of projects in Primavera, assign start date, end date, and person responsible for the task. Manage the Gantt chart and arrive at optimum duration.
- Develop, implement, and forecast project roadmaps with efficient utilization of time and resources right from studying the projects, investigating the updated drawings for the execution of changes, and maintaining quality assurance, to completion of the project.
- Formulate tenders for contractors/subcontractors, evaluate the offers, conduct techno-commercial discussions & finalize the contract given the project schedule.
- Clarify all the techno commercial specifications to team, contractor, client, and management prior to execution of work, in order to avoid any disputes. In case of disputes resolve and manage complex claims on major contracts to effectively meet organizational goals and Company objectives.
- Tailor the negotiations with suppliers and sub-contractors to optimize the project's budget and timely completion of the project.
- Oversee and supervise construction project progress and provide reports on the timeline, progress, and adjustments; compile and plan a budget, cost estimates, and other financial estimates.
- Review the project's financial requirement, keep a record of all the capital spent on the project, make Monthly finance reports, and MIS reports, and present these reports to the management for overviewing of the project.
- Plan, schedule, and perform all tasks ensuring consistent delivery of on-time quality output meeting requirements. Strategically solve disputes with critical thinking to avoid future risks in the project.
- Assign weekly targets to sub-ordinates and conduct weekly reviews for evaluation of their performances.
- Coordinate subcontractors and the construction team to meet contractual conditions of performance. Approve sub-contractors and vendors' invoices.
- Communicate with the responsible parties to ensure quality construction exceeds company standards and proper industry techniques and processes are utilized while ensuring the client's needs and wants are efficiently met.
- Manage third-party contractors including safety oversight, environmental, design specification compliance, and similar construction specifications and requirements
- Visit sites on regular basis for supervision, and tracking of the progress of the project. Arrange/ attend meetings with management and clients to report the progress and plan further activities. Give inputs regarding the execution of work. Track and update the status of the project on Primavera on regular basis, follow-ups with a

- team, consultants, and professionals to keep up with project status, and guide teams to get the work done on time.
- Prepare and update the final project documentation, and reports for a smooth transfer to the client process. Assign surveyor to take actual measurements, and kept track of the valuation of variations in contractors' bills, for accurate payment of contractors.
- ❖ Prepare completion reports, certificates, and work done bills to be submitted to the client.

PROJECTS:			
ORGANIZATION	PROJECT TITLE	VALUATON	
Aarvee Associates	GMRCL Ahmedabad Phase -II Works.		1000Cr
L&T Construction	WDFCC Railway Formation & Structures Work		1020 Cr
Gayatri Projects Ltd	DMRCL Metro & WDFCC Railway Formation & Structures Work.		580 Cr
Gayatri Projects Ltd	SW Drainage System and RMHS & Coal Yard works at TATA Steel Plant Kalinganagar.		440 Cr
Gayatri Projects Ltd	RMHS Civil Works and Internal Roads at TATA Steel Plant		260 Cr
Rohini Construction	Madduvalasa reservoir, Canal networking System Works		52 Cr
Ratna Infrastructures Pvt Ltd	Mechanical Store, Electrical Store & reformation of Plant Drainage System BSP Bhilai		56 Cr
Ratna Infrastructures	Irrigation Works in CG, Kharsia canal Distributaries		58 Cr
Pvt Ltd	system		
APR&Co	Rani Avanthi Bhai Project, Jabalpur, Canal Works		36 Cr

PERSONAL IN	IFORMATION				
Date of Birth:	17 March 1983	Nationality: Indian	Marital Status: Married	Location Preferred:	PAN India
Present salary: Perks	30.00 Lacs .+	Expected in India: 36.00 lacs	Overseas: 90 lacs.+ Perks		

Areas of Work Exposure

- Construction of Railway & Road Formation and structure works.
- Construction of Major and Minor Bridge of Rail, Road & Canal works.
- Construction of Special Bridges (Cable Stay Bridge/ Extra Dose).
- Construction of Heavy/ industrial foundation works.
- Construction of Canals & structures (aqueduct, DLRB and CD.) works.
- Construction of industrial building works.

Awards & Achievements

- Life award-2020 at L&T WDFCC works.
- Appreciation for SWDS at TATA Steel works kalinganagr.
- Project Management (PMI)
- Six Sigma certification (Internal L&T ATL Next.)
- Business Management Expert Certification (ICTRD)

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the details furnished above are true and to the best of my knowledge and belief.

SADINENINARESH